this problem has given us an array
and a number we need to write some code
to
determine whether the given number is
included in the array
one simple way to do this is to iterate
through the array
we can use the each method to do this
each element of the array will be passed
to the block as an
argument let's call that parameter
num
now within the block we want to compare
each element of this array or
num to the local variable number that
was initialized on line
two
if num is equal to number
then we want to output a message to the
user
we'll use string interpolation
to output that the number in this case 3
is in the array
so the condition we've provided to this
if statement
is the comparison on line five that will
return either true
or false if it returns true
we'll output a message to the user
let's run our code
3 is in the array
now if i were to change number let's say
to
8 and run this code again we expect no
output
and that's what we see
that's because the number eight is not
in our array
now this code on lines four through
eight manually checks our array
to see if any of its elements are equal
to number
there's also an array method we could
use
the array include method will return a
boolean
true if its argument is in the calling
array
and false if it's not to demonstrate
this
let's just call include on our array
and we'll pass in number as the argument
i'm using
p on line four to output the return
value of this method invocation
so we'll run our code and we see true
and that's because 3 is in our array
one more time i'm going to assign number
to 8
instead which is not part of our array
and now we'll expect to see false
so now that we know how the include
method works
we can use an if statement to output a
message to the user
similarly to what we did in our previous
solution
the return value of invoking the include
method on line
4 will determine whether or not the code
on line 5
within our if statement is executed if
it returns true
again we'll output a message to the user
if it returns false no message will be
output
let's run our code
and we see that 3 is in the array
be sure to check out ruby's array
documentation
to learn about include and other
commonly used methods